Hi everybody. Today's Tuesday, December
9th, 2025 and our dear friend John
Kuryako is here with us. Welcome back,
John.
>> Thanks so much for having me.
Let me start John with the case of
Charlie Kirk and every time we hear we
hear someone from FBI talking about it
and the only journalist as I know is
pursuing is somehow
investigating the case of Charlie Kirk
is Candace Owens. She's doing everything
to find out who was behind the
assassination of Charlie Kirk, which is
so important to the people, the basis,
the foundation of MAGA movement who
voted for Donald Trump, the current
administration.
And here is what Cash Patel said on
Megan Kelly show about the case of
Charlie Kirk.
>> Let me start with this, the most
obvious. Do you believe that we have the
proper suspect in custody? Do you
believe that Tyler Robinson is in fact
the man who killed Charlie Kirk?
>> Yes.
>> Do you believe he acted with the help of
anyone else?
>> This investigation is being led by the
Utah state authorities because it is a
murder investigation. So the FBI is a
supporting role in the investigative
process. And so what we're doing is the
same thing we did in the pipeline
investigation. The investigation's
ongoing for us. If there's any new leads
or tips, we are exhausting them with
search warrants and legal process. But
at the same time, we are working with
the prosecutors in Utah to make sure we
don't screw up their investigation
because again, the worst outcome would
be if the guy that killed Charlie Kurt
walks out of a United States courtroom
in the state of Utah. And so, it's a
delicate balance again, but there is no
way this FBI is going to stop that
investigation until it reaches its
allcon.
>> Do you believe any foreign government
had a role in his assassination? At this
time, the FBI doesn't have credible
information to connect any foreign
governments to it. But as I said, we are
continuing to take investigative leads.
We're not done. Just because we arrest
someone, just like in the pipe bomber
case, we don't just say, "Okay, we're
done. On to the next." The
investigation, investigative team
continues to work with the Utah
authorities, and they're deriving their
own leads and coming back to us and say,
"Hey, can you look at this piece of
information? Can we get a search warrant
on this account? What about this
individual who is located in X, Y, or Z?
We're tracking all that down.
>> Do you have any credible reason to
believe that anyone connected with the
Turning Point organization had anything
to do with Charlie's death?
>> Zero.
>> Um, on the subject, there's been an
allegation made by prominent podcaster
Candace Owens that she is she's received
a death threat, a credible death threat
from the French. that um a threat has
been made on her life and that the
French, she's been told, also may have
had a role in Charlie's assassination.
Have you looked into either of those? Do
you believe she's received a credible
death threat from the French or that the
French had something potentially to do
with Charlie's death?
>> Any American that receives a death
threat from overseas or anywhere in
America is going to be fully
investigated. So, we're not going to
turn our eye away from that
investigation or any others. If there's
anything to it, this FBI will respond to
it.
Yeah, I think yeah, John, how first he
said that he believes that the guy Tyler
Robinson has assassinated Charlie Kirk.
Then he said that the investigation is
going on instead of you, they're doing
this and that, but how you can say 100%
is this guy, but the investigation is
not done yet.
What is your understanding of what's
going on with the case of Charlie Kirk?
I should preface my comments by saying
that I don't have any inside
information. I'm seeing the same kind of
information that you're seeing. Uh based
on what the state of Utah has released,
it seems like Tyler Robinson was the was
the person who killed Charlie Kirk. Uh
he said to his friends in advance that
he was going to kill Charlie Kirk. after
he did it, he uh he texted his
girlfriend and said that he had killed
Charlie Kirk and they've gotten him.
Like you, I'm very interested in these
other avenues that may or may not be
pursued right now. I can tell you that
in my own case, um
once I was charged with a crime,
the FBI just stopped. they just stopped
and they moved on to the next person.
Um, why they are
continuing to investigate
uh when there doesn't seem to be any
evidence that others were involved is is
interesting to me. I I don't understand
why. He did say something very important
at the beginning, Nema. He said that the
state of Utah is handling this case. I
said from the very beginning that I just
simply did not understand why the FBI
was involved in the investigation into
the Charlie Kirk assassination. The
alleged shooter is from Utah. The crime
took place in Utah. The shooter started
the crime, began the crime in Utah,
driving from the south to the north to
carry out the shooting. This is a state
crime. It has nothing to do with the
FBI. So, I was glad that Cash Patel was
uh was very clear in that the FBI is a
support organization for the state of
Utah. It's not leading this case. Uh and
I I think that's why we're not getting
any more information. I mean, you know
as well as I do, there's been almost
nothing released since the the days
immediately following Charlie Kirk's
assassination.
I think it's because it's a state case
and the state just has chosen not to
release any information.
They didn't even mention we don't know
if they have evaluated his buddy you
know if you know they there has to be
these sort of investigations going on
but as you've mentioned there is nothing
coming out of FBI or the state
department or somewhere I don't know I
said this the state of Utah publishing
anything of that sort that's why
everybody's you know these podcasters
are talking about what has happened
where where is the evidence evidence
for, you know, we had Larry Johnson on
this podcast arguing that there are a
lot of evidence, you know, that shows
the opposite way that shows that the
guy, you know, Tyler Robertson would not
be the the assassin, would not be the
guy who killed Charlie. But after all
there has to be some sort of you know
clarification on the part of the FBI for
example which was since the you know
since the the investigation has started
they have they've been involved in the
whole process but nothing is coming out
even cash you look at the responses that
he's given on this podcast it's just
two words you know nothing more than
that no
>> exactly that's why that brings a lot of
doubts in the mind of those people who
are hearing these people
>> and Dan Bonino did the same thing about
a week ago he was asked repeatedly he
gave one-word answers and just said that
there was nothing else to um to release
he said that uh that as a uh a news
commentator when he was a news
commentator yes of course he could opine
and offer up his views or his ideas or
his analysis as the deputy director of
the FBI, he has to follow the evidence.
And he said there is just no evidence
that anybody else was involved. Now, if
I hope you don't mind my saying this,
before we started um the live stream,
you and I were having a conversation
offline and we were talking about how
in the old days, let's say around the
days of the Kennedy assassination,
people believed their government. People
wanted to believe that the government
was telling the truth. And now in 2025,
people don't believe that the government
is telling the truth. They always
believe that there's more to the story
because in fact over the years that has
proven to be the case. And so I can
understand why people are just not
accepting this notion that uh that that
uh Tyler Robinson was acting alone. I
can understand why people want to see
information leading to a hidden hand in
a in a killing as high-profile as
Charlie Kirks.
>> Yeah. Here is what Candace Owens said
>> John.
>> There's been an allegation made by
>> this FBI will respond to it.
>> Okay. But so far, no.
>> So, we are just looking at everything
that comes in. We're not going to reject
any piece of information. If someone
feels that their life is being
threatened, we are of course looking at
it.
>> Uh do you want to involve me in you
looking at it? Because actually it kind
of left me on red. There has been no
communication with uh the FBI. You are
aware right there. Megan Kelly is asking
you directly about it. So you can't
pretend you didn't receive it and you
are choosing to skip over. He completely
skips over the part about me uh having
asserted which Megan asks him directly,
you know, was France involved in
childhood assassination. He doesn't even
address that. Skips right over it and
instead says if any American has a
threat, that's what we're here for. And
she's like, okay, but was there actually
a threat on can if anybody let's just
kind of make it state it more broadly,
we will take it seriously. Well, you're
not doing that, Cash Patel. And I find
it very odd that I said that I had proof
that French is that that the the
government of France was involved in
Charlie Hir's assassination that they
were on the ground that day and you have
not reached out to me in this very
interview that you are asserting that
you are certain that Tyler Robinson is
the only person involved. How can you be
certain if you are not reaching out to
people that claim to have verifiable
evidence which could dispute that
narrative?
Does it seem to you like he's telling
the truth there? Does it seem to you
like he's being open and he's being
transparent? Or does it seem like he's
intentionally being cy because he knows
that I am telling the truth despite the
many millions of dollars that is being
spent on this Operation Mockingbird 2.0
campaign? Cash Patel knows that I am
telling the truth.
>> Yeah, [laughter]
she's just
>> and Mrs. Mcronone is a man.
[laughter]
Go ahead, John.
>> What What can you say? I I'll start by
saying I believe that Candace Owens
believes that this is an international
conspiracy.
I do not think it's an international
conspiracy. I would be surprised if the
French government even knew who Charlie
Kirk was. I highly, highly doubt that
the French government wanted Charlie
Kirk dead or had any reason to make
Charlie Kirk dead. It just doesn't make
any sense. You know, Candace Owens says
that she has irrefutable proof. She also
said she had irrefutable proof that the
Italian government stole the 2020
election from Donald Trump.
I remember that because I was on the
conference call when she said it and
that as soon as this irrefutable proof
was released to the public, it would
bring down the Italian government and
Donald Trump would be uh inaugurated
again on January the 20th, 2021. Of
course, that was ridiculous and none of
it ever happened. So, Candace Owens has
a has a great following. She has
millions of people that listen to her.
She's very, very bright,
but she comes up with a lot of crazy
stuff. She claims to have irrefutable
proof and then she never puts up.
>> Yeah.
But if something she says that she has
been threatened by the government in
France because
>> right
>> what is that? If something of that sort
is happening, what is the role of FBI or
CIA? Do they really consider
>> That's a good question and it's actually
it's actually something that I'm glad
she brought up because I I'll give you
my own um experience too. I am nowhere
near the league of uh of Candace Owens,
but I get death threats on a regular
basis as well. I'm I'm out there like
you are on the internet. I'm former CIA.
Some people love me, some people hate
me, so I get death threats. I report
every single threat to the FBI on the
FBI's um web page where that they have a
a drop- down menu you can report crimes.
The FBI has never ever reached out to me
ever. Not a single time. They don't care
that John Kiryaku is getting death
threats just like they don't care if
Candace Owens is getting death threats.
They don't have the manpower to care
when they have major crimes that they're
that they're investigating. Um, so do I
believe she got death threats? Yeah. And
I believe that she believes the threats
came from the French government. They
came probably from some guy who was
drinking too much and may or may not
have had a French accent and, you know,
who emailed her or called her in the
middle of the night. I'll tell you, just
a few days ago, I got a death threat. 3.
It was 3:25 a.m. I don't have my ringer
on in the middle of the night. So, this
idiot called me, threatened to kill me
in a voicemail, and he used his own
phone, his his cell phone. Well, I have
been verified. So, I went to
binverified.com.
I put in the phone number. It gives me
his name, his address, his phone number,
and uh it confirmed the phone number and
um his uh social media. So rather than
report it to the FBI cuz they do
nothing, I texted him and I told him
that if he ever did something like that
again,
I was going to tear off his head and
shove his head up his ass and I said,
"And I'm going to do that at 321 Main
Street." I put his home address.
He immediately messaged me back and he
said, "I'm so sorry. I was drunk. I
don't like you and I watch your videos
and they made me angry and I found your
number online and I said, "Yeah, don't
do it again because next time I'm not
going to be so nice about it and I
haven't heard back, but the FBI is not
going to do it for you. The FBI is not
going to protect you." I still don't
think that she was threatened by the
French government. That wouldn't make
any sense at all. And I'll tell you one
other thing about the French.
When I was at the CIA,
the French DGSSE, the the uh French
Intelligence Service had a reputation
whereby they would take care of
people that they considered to be a
problem very quickly and very quietly.
So, if you were an al-Qaeda figure in
the Sahel, you were going to get a
bullet in your brain. And the French
weren't going to make threats about it
in advance. They were just going to go
in and kill you. Uh if you were an
anti-French environmental activist in
the South Pacific, they're going to blow
up your boat and they're going to kill
everybody on it. They don't need to make
a preface. They don't need to call and
threaten you and warn you. If the French
want you dead, you're going to be dead.
And that's why I don't think she was
threatened by the French government.
They don't make threats.
Yeah,
John,
you've mentioned the Middle East. When
you look at this situation in the Middle
East today and
you you have a lot experience and you
know the region,
these officers, CIA officers that go to
the Middle East, do they have any sort
of
strategy? Do they know of the US
strategy in the Middle East or they're
they're giving them some sort of
missions, some sort of, you know, duties
to to
>> right?
>> What is that? Because after all, when
you are a a CIA officer or someone who's
working for CIA,
you you just see that as a duty or you
want to know a bigger picture of what's
going on? Because
>> that's a great question, Nema. That's
that's an important question. Um, first
of all, most of the officers that the
CIA sends to the Middle East um are not
Middle East experts and do not speak
Arabic.
>> Um, almost none of the CIA's officer
officers in the Middle East have a
long-term view. And it's because the
American government usually does not
have a long-term view. The CIA has
something called operating directives,
OD, and it goes from a level zero, which
means they're coming over the embassy
walls right now, to level five, which
means, you know, if you happen to hear
anything about, you know, growing corn
in Morocco,
just send us a a little message. So
tier zero level zero is the most
important that is like nuclear
proliferation
uh Iran
uh
the war in Russia and Ukraine that kind
of thing is tier zero tier one means
drop what you're doing and focus on this
and it's things like terrorism for
example
uh or threats to an American embassy And
then it goes down from there, tier 2,
three, four, to the point where it's
nobody really cares about the lower
tiers. But that's not to say that any of
these tiers are for a long-term view.
This was one of the things that I
enjoyed the most when I was serving in
the Middle East as an as an analyst.
It's because your job was to look at the
long-term view. I was interested in,
let's say, Saudi stability over the next
30 years. That's interesting to me.
What's not interesting is what's going
to happen in the next 24 hours in Sudan,
for example. I I I really don't care.
But a lot of CIA people do care. And so,
they're going to be focused on Sudan in
the next 24 hours or the next 48 hours
or what happens in the next round of
talks in Libya, as another example.
um or what's happening is Yemen going to
split back into two different Yemens.
Um and I think that that frankly it does
a disservice to the policy maker because
the policy maker for the most part can
get that information by reading the New
York Times or Al Jazzer or the
Washington Post. So the CIA is not
adding anything to the body of
intelligence. It should be focused on
the long term and it's not.
And whose decision is that for this sort
of policy? Is that coming from the
president and his office?
>> Yeah, it it originates in the National
Security Council. So these are supposed
to be the issues that are the most um
important for the president and for
policy makers at that level, the
secretary of state, the secretary of
defense, the the national security
adviser. And then those orders come down
to the CIA director and from the C CIA
director to the um operational division
directors. So every year in December,
let's say I'm working for Neareastern
operations, the division director is
going to say, "Okay, everybody in the
Near East division, this is what we're
going to collect on over the next year.
We're going to collect on Iran and the
nuclear program and Syria and what's
what China's doing in the Middle East,
things like that, things that that are
the most important. And then if you
happen to pick up something that is less
important but still interesting, write
it down, send it in, and we'll let the
analysts have it.
Then are they gonna do they consider the
feedback they're getting from their anal
their officers in their for example in
the region you see what is their take
what is their understanding of what this
the situation there because after all
when you have someone on the ground
gathering information his view his sort
of understanding would be important is
that
>> you are so you are so right and the the
obvious answer should yes, that they're
very focused on that. Unfortunately, the
true answer is no. They don't care. And
I'll give you an example. This is a
dated example. I I was writing a paper.
I was still on the analytic side. I was
writing a paper
um that touched on women's uh role in
politics in a Middle Eastern country.
And there was one woman in particular
that I was very interested in because
she she was out there in the media all
the time fighting for the women's right
to vote and um and a real leader where
the international media were seeking her
out and getting her opinion and she was
very outspoken. She would come to the
United States and speak to women's
groups. So I sent a cable through uh
there's a uh a a tasking office at the
CIA. So, I went to this tasking office
and I said, "I have these eight
questions about this woman. Could you
send the questions to the station and
have the station assign an officer to
find the information that I need?" So,
they did. And about 3 weeks later, I got
a very short cable in response to my
questions and it said, "Oh, yes. Uh,
this woman is well known to us. We call
her the hot dog lady because we
understand that when she was living in
the United States, she loved hot dogs.
And here in the Middle East, it's hard
to find hot dogs. And so she has them
shipped from somewhere, Beirut or
something. And she likes them with
mustard and relish and this and that.
And I'm like, "What the [__] are you
talking about? This I can't send this to
the president."
And so I went back to the tasking office
and I said, "This was a complete failure
to collect the information necessary to
send to the president. I can't tell the
president in response to his question,
should I take this woman seriously
because she wants to meet at the White
House?" I can't say, "Well, I don't know
if you should take her seriously, but
she really loves hot dogs and this is
what she likes on her hot dogs."
That was when I learned that there was a
real split between the director of
operations and the director of
intelligence and the director of
operations was going to do its thing and
it didn't care what the director of
intelligence was writing and sending to
the president.
Yeah, John, one of the the reason I
asked you this question is the situation
in Ukraine
because we know what's going on in
Ukraine in terms of the what is
happening to the military of Ukraine is
you know Russia is somehow
advancing underground but
how how do you see the role of the CIA
in gathering ing information from
Ukraine on the ground, the information
that are firsthand information. I'm not
talking about they're getting it from,
you know, British or any other
intelligence. Are they really getting
the information
directly from from Ukraine or they're
getting through these channels? It's
it's my understanding that there are CIA
officers, senior CIA officers stationed
inside the Ukrainian intelligence
service to provide support and liaison.
Uh and there are CIA officers on the
ground with Ukrainian um military or
special forces units. In addition, we
know that the CIA is training Ukrainian
U military officers here in the United
States at bases in te Texas and I think
North Carolina. Uh so yeah, the the CIA
is getting the information directly from
the horse's mouth. But
uh but the Ukrainians are losing.
This war is untenable.
Every observer will tell you that the
Russians control the the line of
demarcation
and in the end CIA or no CIA, the
Ukrainians are going to have to come to
some kind of an agreement with the
Russians. This is one of those
situations, Nema, where the CIA is not
going to be able to to win this thing
for for the Ukrainians. This is going to
have to be between the Russians and the
Ukrainians. And sure, CIA help may have
may have delayed a Russian victory, may
have cost the Russians, you know, more
casualties,
but it can't go on forever.
>> Yeah.
John,
we know what has happened in 2014 in
Ukraine with the coup,
>> but do you see the same sort of policy
happening in the aftermath of any
Ukrainian settlement? Because what
Russia sees in Ukraine today is they
want a permanent solution to the case of
Ukraine and a security architecture for
the region.
You you cannot you know make obstacles
for CIA, MI6 or these intelligence. So
Russian intelligence as well. They're
doing their job. You know it's it's
common. It's you know it's normal to do
that. But when it comes to the
securities of these superpowers, you
have to have some sort of limitation to
the activities that you're, you know,
committed to.
Is that going to be considered? Do you
do you see that sort of will in the
Trump administration to consider that?
>> I think so. I agree with you. Whatever
solution
the two sides come to in the end, it has
to be a permanent solution. And I think
we've seen the indications of what that
solution is going to be. It's going to
have to be that the Russians keep
Donetsk Luhansk uh Kerone Crimea. The
Russian speaking areas that they control
de facto now. I think they'll end up
controlling uh uh formally
once this is over.
I think that another Russian red line is
that Ukraine cannot ever be a member of
NATO. But that's a misnomer, Nema,
because Ukraine doesn't have to be a
member of NATO. Uh Australia is not a
member of NATO. Japan, South Korea,
Saudi Arabia, UAE, they're not members
of NATO. They're what's called major
non-NATO allies. That's an official
status. And I wouldn't be surprised if
the United States agrees with the
Russians that no, Ukraine should not be
a member of NATO. It will never be a
member of NATO. But it could be granted
major non-NATO ally status, thus giving
it essentially the same rights as a NATO
country. And I think what the Russians
will concede is that Ukraine will get
fasttrack um uh membership in the
European Union. And then the EU begins
the rebuilding of Ukraine and that's
going to be the end of it. But I I
really do believe that
we're nearing the end and the end is not
going to be what the United States and
Ukraine have hoped for, but it's going
to be enough to put this thing to to
rest.
>> Yeah. Many people believe,
at least in our audience, that CIA is
part of deep state.
CIA is, you know,
do you think that the leadership usually
in CIA is part of the establishment or
the the establishment has a lot of
leverage on CIA in the way that they're
using CIA?
>> No, I I I agree that there is a deep
state and the CIA's an important
probably the most important part of the
deep state. But let's let's define what
a deep state is. In my view, a deep
state is a group of unelected,
very powerful bureaucrats
that can do what the president wants or
they can ignore what the president wants
because presidents come and go every
four years or every eight years. And
these deep state leaders are in their
positions for 20, 30, even 35 years.
Presidents come and go and these deep
sters remain. And so if there's a policy
that a president supports or wants and
it's a policy that the deep state
leadership does not like, they just wait
until the president's not president
anymore.
>> They did that during the first Trump
administration.
>> That's exactly what they did. You're
exactly right. That's what we saw.
Mhm.
>> What is the
relationship between for example the
position of Tulsi Gabbard and the head
of CIA and how they interact and who has
the upper hand,
>> right? So Tulsi Gabbard is the director
of national intelligence. John Ratcliffe
of course is the director of the CIA.
the CIA director technically falls
underneath the DNI, but in reality, on a
day-to-day basis, that's just not true.
Depending on who happens to be
president, the CIA director can be a
member of the cabinet. Um, he is a
member of the of this cabinet.
Presidents can choose, for example,
among CIA director, DNI, and ambassador
to the United Nations, who gets a
cabinet position. Um,
the way the office of the DNI was first
established, the DNI was supposed to be
the overall coordinator of all of the 18
intelligence agencies in the US
government. 18 intelligence agencies in
the US government. What that meant for
all practical purposes was that the DNI
had control over the budget. But don't
forget that fully half of those
intelligence agencies are actually parts
of the Pentagon. And so in the end, the
DNI doesn't have authority over those.
The Secretary of Defense has authority
over those. Um over the years, over the
last 20 years,
more and more authority has been
absorbed by the DNI. The President's
Daily Brief used to be a CIA only
publication. Now it's a DNI publication.
uh major operations Iran, Iraq,
Afghanistan, Russia, China used to be
solely the domain of the CIA. Now they
fall under the DNI. So it's almost as
though we have two CIA directors who are
competing with each other for primacy.
So far,
this has been very quiet in the Trump
administration, but it looks like John
Ratcliffe has not had the PR problems
that Tulsi Gabbard has had. I've heard
rumors recently that
uh Pete Hgse will likely not be
Secretary of Defense for very much
longer and that Tulsi Gabbard might
become the Secretary of Defense.
We have to wait and see. But the bottom
line is
that there's no clear
division between DNI and CIA.
It's just something that is fought out
on an ad hoc basis.
But we know that Tulsi Gabbert is not
happy with the case of, for example,
Venezuela. She came out and said that
the regime change doesn't work.
>> The United States doesn't benefit from
regime change.
>> Correct. But on the other hand, you see
the policy of the Trump administration
is somehow is the regime change. They're
they're officially saying that, you
know, not just the Trump administration.
Most of Republicans who are in line with
the Trump administration, they say that
regime change, Maduro must go,
>> right?
>> And which is which is a a stab to the
heart of the MAGA movement. This is
where the progressive left and the MAGA
right meet and agree
no foreign interventions.
And you know this is different from
Iraq, Afghanistan, so many other places
where the US has intervened. We don't
we're not at war with Venezuela.
The Venezuelans are no threat to us. And
regardless of what the administration is
saying, Venezuela is not an originator
of drugs. And the drugs that do pass
through Venezuela, primarily from
Colombia and Ecuador, are on their way
to West Africa for then trans shshipment
to Western Europe. Those drugs don't
come to the United States. My own view
is this is all about China. And I I'll
explain why. Venezuela sits on an ocean
of oil. That oil is very, very dirty.
It's full of sulfur and it requires
specialty refining using very heavy
chemicals. Well, that specialty refining
until about 5 years ago could only be
done at refineries in Houston, Texas.
And then we put sanctions on the
Venezuelan oil industry. Well, the
Indians and the Chinese both built
refineries that could purify dirty
Venezuelan oil. And about 5 years ago,
the Chinese announced that they were
going to build a refinery to process
Venezuelan oil in the Caribbean.
Well, we can't admit we were wrong and
lift sanctions.
So, what what can we do to save face? we
overthrow Maduro, try to install a a
friendly uh puppet government, lift
sanctions, and we start refining
Venezuelan oil anymore. So, I think this
is really about China more than anything
else.
>> Yeah, I think the question would be the
day after Maduro is gone, who's going to
be there? And how can you be sure that
she's gonna be the [laughter]
>> It's not going to be Juan Guyaido whom
nobody had ever heard of. It's not going
to be this woman that just won the Nobel
Peace Prize of all things.
>> No.
>> Um
>> Maria Machado.
>> Thank you. Maria Machado. I couldn't
remember. I couldn't even remember her
name. Um
yeah, I think that see this is a lesson
that we just seem to never learn.
It's it's easy to overthrow a
government, right? I mean, they actually
teach you in at West Point
the the
modus operendi by which you can
overthrow a government. You have to take
control of the presidential palace and
either arrest, kill or exile the leader.
You have to take control of the radio
and television stations. You have to
take control of the major intersections
in the capital. And you have to have the
support of the military. Well, we don't
have the support of the Venezuelan
military.
Maduro has the support of the Venezuelan
military. So what does that mean? Does
that mean we have to send in ground
troops and and fight a hot war on the
ground in Venezuela when the Venezuelans
are no threat to us?
So I I just don't see any upside to a to
a policy of trying to overthrow the
Venezuelan government.
>> Yeah. Here is John. Here is what Donald
Trump said about Venezuela
>> are numbered and that the US could soon
strike Venezuelan territory. Could we
see American troops on the ground in
Venezuela?
>> I don't comment on that. I wouldn't say
that one way or the other. I can say
this that he sent us millions of people,
many from prisons, many drug dealers and
drug lords, uh mental institution people
in mental institutions. He sent him into
our country where we have a where we had
a very stupid president. You know that
Biden's a low IQ person, especially
nowadays. I mean, he was low IQ 30 years
ago, but he was especially low IQ now.
And uh what he did to our country is not
good. Trenagua,
the gangs, one of the meanest gangs in
the world.
>> You've locked down the the the border
now.
>> He sent a lot of these people. He also
sent in a lot of drugs. So, we'll see
how it all works out. So do
>> I can't talk about
>> So how far would you go to to take
Maduro?
>> Yeah, John. The only thing that he has
not blamed on
Joe Biden is the way that he's sleeping
right now when people are talking.
[laughter]
>> That's right.
>> That's right. know every time any issue
that he's talking about on you know he's
he's mentioning Joe Biden and his
administration but you are the president
of the United States right now and
people wants you to you know to to do
whatever you have in your mind they're
not talking about Joe Biden and what was
happening during the Joe Biden and his
administration
>> right
>> what is behind I was talking with a
psychologist about this sort of attitude
on the part of Donald Trump. I know that
you are trained in this direction. When
you see someone like President Trump,
you know, he's the president of the, you
know, the United States, why does he
need every time to bring up Joe Biden to
somehow legitimize what he's doing?
>> I think it's a personality quirk of his.
Um,
I think that that he thinks it it helps
to legitimize his policies. And I think
that he sees it as a way of explaining
uh his policies that that Joe Biden's
policies were so bad that they all need
to be scrapped or they all need to be
fixed or changed. He's going to do it,
but he's being forced to do it because
the Biden policies were so bad and Joe
Biden is low IQ president and and Joe
Biden was, you know, in dementia and I
don't know. Um
I I will point out that none of what he
said related to
to the emptying of prisons and mental
institutions and sending people to the
United States. None of that is true.
That was true of the Cubans in 1978 and
1979 and the Mariel boat lift where the
Cubans really did empty their prisons
and their mental institutions and put
them on boats and send them to Florida.
Um there's no evidence that that's ever
happened coming from Venezuela.
John, with the regime change, you you
know about Iraq, Afghanistan, Libya,
right now Syria, we had the regime
change. And when it comes to Venezuela,
people here in Brazil, in Latin America,
there's so much concern about what's
going on in Venezuela, if that would
bring some sort of chaos in the region
the way that it was in the war in Iraq
and Afghanistan,
>> right?
What what is your take on
and and the sort of chaos that could
bring this sort of conflict could bring
to the region and how is it going to be
beneficial to the United States after
all? because Maduro is saying that he's
prepared to particip to cooperate with
the United States if they want all he's
going to send if they want to in to
somehow
you know invest in Venezuela's you know
economy they're open to that there is no
resistance from resistance from you know
the government in Venezuela
>> in fact Maduro and Trump had a telephone
conversation a week ago
you know Nema when when the major powers
of the region, Mexico, Colombia, Brazil
are 100% against any American
intervention in Venezuela, the Americans
should sit up and take notice. You know,
when
just about every country in the world
has come out and said that they are
against any American military
intervention in Venezuela, then we
should we should learn the lesson.
there. I honestly I don't see anything
positive that comes out of a military
intervention. It really will destabilize
uh northern South America. Uh it is
going to damage our diplomatic relations
with all of the countries that I just
mentioned. And this is a more minor
point, but I think still an important
one. The country of Guyana has just
discovered that it is also sitting on an
ocean of oil. that it is just now
starting to lift with the help of
American, Dutch, and British oil
companies. What happens to the economic
development of Guyana, which sits right
alongside Venezuela?
There's no upside. There's nothing good
that can come out of a military
intervention. And I'm hoping that it's
just bluster.
But I mean, we've sent a carrier battle
group there. you're talking about 11 or
12 battle ready ships. You know, we're
we're only a couple of hours flight to
drop troops or special forces.
So, I I'm I'm worried about where this
is going.
>> Yeah. The the problem, by the way, with
the Trump administration is that they're
not communicating with anybody in Latin
America.
>> No. just the you know the guy in
Argentina you know MLE the only guy
who's close to Washington is the
president of Argentina the other
presidents here in Brazil they're not
that much of communication between
Brazil and you know Colombia the same
because they see these people as radical
left they call it the radical left I
don't know what does that mean anymore
you know we don't have it here in Brazil
you know
>> my best friend from high school is a
MAGA Republican, a a strongly proTrump
Republican. And every time I talk to
him, he talks about the radical left,
the radical left, the radical left. And
I said I said, "I have to ask you, what
is it that's radical about the left?"
And he said, "Oh, all the all their
policies." I said, "No, no. I I'm
serious. I want you to tell me what it
is that's that's radical."
And he said, 'Well, like um
like uh the environment.
>> And I said, 'It's it's radical to want
clean water and clean air. Well,
and then that's it. That's the end of
the conversation because we've gotten to
the point where these words don't mean
anything.
>> You know, I remember at the end of the
George W. Bush administration, the
Republican National Committee circulated
a memo. They got caught circulating a
memo
urging everybody who goes on a
television news program to speak out
against what they called Islamopascism.
Well, the term they just made up the
term at the at the Republican National
Committee and it didn't catch on. It
didn't catch on in part because somebody
leaked the memo and said the Republicans
want us to all say Islamopfascism
so that we have something to to rally
against. And I think that's what we're
we're seeing today with the radical
left, the radical right. There's nothing
radical. I I joke all the time that in
the United States we have two political
parties. We have a right of center party
and we have a farther right of center
party. There's nothing left about the
Democratic Party. It's a capitalist
party.
>> Yeah.
I think there they see socialism as the
radical left because socialism after all
they want to make some sort of you know
situation for those people who are not
able to provide you know they're having
problems but they see this as radical as
they saw it in New York with Zoran
Mandani right
>> you know the whole problem is that
>> I think the oligarchs you know these
people who are you know they they have
the they own everything social media you
you name it everything they have
everything and they want to dominate the
whole you know political system that's
why they call it radical whenever
someone comes out to meet socialist and
I
>> yeah and they don't know the difference
between
>> about socialism I don't see anything
radical
>> no I I'll tell you a funny little story
I I years ago during the Trump's first
term Um,
my then wife and I were at a relative's
house, one of her relatives house for
Thanksgiving dinner. And I was sitting
next to this old woman. She was in her
80s. She had Fox News on. And she says
to me,
"It looks like we're turning into a
communistic country."
And I said, I said, "Yeah, you think
so?" And she said, "All this socialism."
And I said, "You know what? You're
right. This socialism, like social
security, what is social security after
all? It's free money for old people who
were too stupid or too lazy to save for
their old age. I'm against this kind of
socialism." And she looks at me and she
says, "I live on social security." I
said, "But that's a socialistic
program."
And she said, 'Well,
I think we need programs like that. I
said, 'Oh, well, then maybe it's okay if
we're turning into a socialistic
country, but another problem is
Americans have no idea the difference
between socialism and communism. And
I'll give you another example. I read my
small hometown newspaper every every day
and there's a very popular Mexican
restaurant that's there and there was an
article saying that when you go to this
me Mexican restaurant and you leave a
tip, the tip doesn't go to the worker,
it goes to the owner of the restaurant.
And in the comment section under the
article, somebody wrote, "That's
socialism for you." So, I wrote a
comment and I said, "Actually, that's
capitalism. Socialism would be if the
workers owned the restaurant."
And I said, I I took a shot. I couldn't
help it. But I said, "It sounds like
you're in need of a sixth grade
government class if you don't know the
difference between socialism and
capitalism."
But that's America.
That's just the way it is here. People
don't know
>> you know what's amazing here in Brazil
we have some sort of socialist you know
government but what is the main goal
lula government just mentioning before
wrapping up John we have two system
health care system one of them is suss
they call it sus you know everybody's
covered by that and the other one you
pay for that you know
>> ah same in Greece
>> yeah it's amazing John, it's amazing
when you look at the system and how it
works. You know, if someone doesn't have
any sort of, you know,
you know, coverage from the, you know,
insurance and and all the health care
companies, they have it by free, you
know, they don't need to pay anything
and they're going to get the same the
same the pretty same, you know, service.
>> Wow.
I think that's,
you know, many people
>> that's an advanced society right there.
>> It's amazing, John. You have to be here
and, you know, see how it works. And in
my opinion, it works just fine.
>> That's exactly how it is in Greece. The
the health care system is fantastic.
They have a private system. All the
private system does is it gets you moved
closer to the front of the line. So if
you use just the public system and you
need a procedure, maybe it's going to
take 11 or 12 months. If you have the
private system, you can get the
procedure in one or two months. That's
the only difference.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Thank you so much, John, for being with
us. Great pleasure as always.
>> Ah, the pleasure is all mine. I'm always
happy to see you. Thanks for having me.
>> See you, John. Bye-bye.
>> Bye-bye.